Sneha Ramu

Aspiring Analyst

Contact

Cambridge, MA, 02141

857-210-3219

rsneha.official9345@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sneharamu

https://github.com/Sneha0697

Technical skills

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Excel

Excellent

Canva

Microsoft PowerPoint

Python

SQL

Tableau

Very Good

Machine Learning

R - Programming

Good

Skills

Multitasking abilities

Interpersonal Communication

Teamwork

Excellent

Flexible & Adaptable

Leadership

Very Good

Dependable student with experience in competitive and collaborative environments. Pursuing degree in Business Analytics with extensive understanding of various coding languages, Python, R-programming, SQL, Power BI. Industrious and motivated to work independently and as team player. Skilled in working under pressure and adapting to new situations and challenges to best enhance the organizational brand.

Education

Master of Science: Business Analytics

Expected April 2022

Hult International Business School - Boston, MA, USA

- Entrepreneurial Impact and Future Leader scholarship Recipient
- Women+ in Business Club Member

Master of Science: International Business

Sept.,2020 - Aug.,2021

Hult International Business School - Boston, MA

- Specialization in Finance
- Entrepreneurial Impact and Future Leader scholarship Recipient
- Women+ in Business Club Member

Bachelor of Science: Mechanical Engineering

Aug.,2015 - June,2019

Dayananda Sagar College of Engineering

- President of the College sports association
- Thesis: Characterization of Aluminum 6061 Alloy Reinforced with Silicon Carbide

Experience

SOCIAL IMPACT ANALYST

Aug.,2021 - Oct.,2021

Impending Bloom, New York, New York

- Developed 5 reports, each assessing distinct criterion controlling S&P100 companies.
- Used coordination and planning skills to achieve results according to schedule.
- Used Microsoft Word and other software tools to create documents and other communications

College Intern

June,2015 - Jan.,2020

R.S. Technologies, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Participated in cross-functional teams with manufacturing, quality, marketing, and procurement departments.
- Administered day-to-day business activities, meeting internal and external customer needs. Handled 20 calls per week to address customer inquiries and concerns
- Analyzed financial data to identify trends, patterns, and strategies. Saved \$9300 by implementing cost-saving initiatives that addressed long-standing problems
- Sorted and organized files, spreadsheets, and reports.

Accomplishments

Projects

- Used Python to develop a Text Adventure Game
- Marketing Strategy to Small business Company, Pickle Jar Kitchen.
- Future Challenge: Business service named Express Care.
- Human Powered Vehicle Challenge, ASME.
- Dynamic Skills Integrated Program.
- Student Intern at Bharat Earth Movers Ltd Bangalore, Karnataka
- Student Intern at Hyundai Motor India Ltd. Sriperambadur, Tamil Nadu

Awards & Honors

- National Level Basketball Player: Represented Karnataka State team for 6 times.
- Received Bal Rathna Award from state government: Student with Excellence in Academic and Extracurricular activities.
- All India 27th rank: Human Resource Development General Knowledge Quiz